Once more with feeling.
Guardians of the Galaxy Vol. 3 is a science fiction,
adventure, action film directed by James Gunn.
Peter Quill, still reeling from the loss of Gamora, must rally his team around
him to defend the universe along with protecting one of their own.
A mission that, if not completed successfully, could quite possibly
lead to the end of the Guardians as we know them.
Peter Quill / Star-Lord, played by Chris Pratt.
Gamora, played by Zoe Saldaña.
Drax, played by Dave Bautista.
Nebula, played by Karen Gillan.
Mantis, played by Pom Klementieff.
Groot (voice), played by Vin Diesel.
Guardians of the Galaxy Vol.
3 (marketed as Guardians of the Galaxy Volume 3) is a 2023 American superhero film based on the Marvel Comics superhero team
Guardians of the Galaxy, produced by Marvel Studios and distributed by Walt Disney Studios Motion Pictures.
It is the sequel to Guardians of the Galaxy (2014)
and Guardians of the Galaxy Vol.
2 (2017), and the 32nd film in the Marvel Cinematic Universe (MCU).
Written and directed by James Gunn, it features an ensemble cast including Chris Pratt, Zoe Saldaña, Dave Bautista, Karen Gillan, Pom
Klementieff, Vin Diesel, Bradley Cooper, Will Poulter, Sean Gunn, Chukwudi Iwuji, Linda Cardellini, Nathan Fillion, and Sylvester Stallone.
In the film, the other Guardians race to save the life of Rocket (Cooper) from his creator, the
High Evolutionary (Iwuji), who is an alien scientist trying to perfect the universe.
James Gunn had initial ideas for a third and final Guardians of the Galaxy film by November
2014, and announced his return to write and direct in April 2017 ahead of Vol.
2's release.
3 explores the origin story of Rocket, with whom Gunn personally identifies.
Disney fired Gunn from Vol.
3 in July 2018 after controversial jokes he made on Twitter resurfaced.
Gunn received support from several cast members, and the
studio reversed course by that October.
His return was publicly revealed in March 2019, and he restarted work on the film after completing his film The
Suicide Squad (2021) and the first season of its spin-off series Peacemaker (2022) for DC Films.
New cast members, including Iwuji and Poulter, joined by the start of filming, which took
place at Trilith Studios in Atlanta, Georgia, from November 2021 to May 2022.
Guardians of the Galaxy Vol.
3 premiered at Disneyland Paris on April 22, 2023, and was released in the
United States on May 5, as part of Phase Five of the MCU.
Like its predecessors, it was a critical and commercial success, with many
deeming it to be a satisfactory conclusion to the trilogy.
It grossed over $845.6 million worldwide, becoming the
fourth-highest-grossing film of 2023.
At the 96th Academy Awards, the film was nominated for Best Visual Effects.
The film explores themes of hero, superhero,
melancholy, mad scientist, based on comic.
The tone is lighthearted and uplifting and thought_provoking.